Chester Rivas

Front End Developer

Toronto, ON M3A 3A8
C: 416-524-5815
E: chester.rivas@gmail.com
W: crivas.net

BACKGROUND: I'm a Front End Developer who started off his career as a web-designer, later moved into Flash Development and now a passion for various front end technologies such as JavaScript Frameworks like Knockout.js and Angular.js. I would classify myself as a Front End Developer with an eye for exceptional design and user experience. I've had previous team lead experience. I'm also very interested in learning backend technologies.

SKILLS MATRIX

- JQuery EXPERT 3 years
- Knockout.js EXCELLENT 3 years
- Angular.js EXCELLENT 1 year
- JavaScript EXCELLENT 8 years
- Responsive Web Design EXPERT 2 vears
- Grunt EXCELLENT 2 years
- Bootstrap EXPERT 2 years

- SASS/CSS3 EXPERT 3 years
- HTML5 EXCELLENT 3 years
- FB Application EXCELLENT 3 years
- PHP BASIC 1 year
- Photoshop EXCELLENT 8 years
- Illustrator PROFICIENT 7 years
- HTML EXPERT 8 years
- CSS EXPERT 8 years

- XML EXPERT 8 years
- ASP.NET BASIC 2 years
- ActionScript 3.0 (OOP) EXPERT 7 vears

SKILL SUMMARY

- · expert knowledge in JavaScript
- expert in RWD
- well rounded in several JavaScript frameworks (Knockout.js, Angular.js, Sproutcore, Ember.js, RequireJS, Codelgniter, Symfony2)
- experience in using and building custom JQuery plugins
- work every day with Git and Grunt

- expert in HTML, CSS, Photoshop
- expert in handling other developer's code
- worked in agile development environment (scrum)
- managed multiple tasks in a pressured environment while adhering to strict deadlines
- heavy focus on communication, organization and documentation
- op very quick learner, creative and resourceful and highly motivated
 - object oriented developing best practices and coding conventions
 - familiar with code design pattern such as singletons, MVC, Factory, MVVM.
 - intermediate understand of backend technologies

NOTABLE CLIENTS

- TMN
- Just Eat
- Country Deep
- Kobo
- Workopolis
- McDonald's
- Wal-Mart

- Mitsubishi
- Wayne Gretzky
- Home Depot
- Citi Credit Cards
- VIA Rail
- American Express
- Tommy Hilfiger

- RBC
- Nissan
- Infiniti
- BellTimex
- Bayview Village

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Movie Network CONTRACT

Senior Front End Developer | November 2013 – February 2014

- responsible for all front end development on TMN website redesign
- worked in Symfony2 backend environment
- created custom JQuery plugins
- responsive web-design implementation and optimization
- implemented backend API using Knockout to render on the front end

Jam3 CONTRACT

Senior Front End Developer | September 2013 - November 2013

- developed with Codelgniter PHP framework to maintain backend and code the front end
- created custom functionality in PHP/JavaScript for automatic phase switching at certain times
- implemented styles and created custom JQuery plugins when needed
- worked with RequireJS to implement static page animations and transitions with TweenMax
- integrated Grunt.js tasks for release packages
- implemented designs and worked with proprietary internal JavaScript Framework

Great Gulf CONTRACT

Senior Front End Developer | May 2013 - September 2013

- updated and maintained front and back end of numerous company websites
- lead developer on multiple projects
- worked closely with CTO and Technical Director
- mentored and guided junior developers
- implemented methods for improving workflow, efficiency and organization

Motion Season CONTRACT

Lead Front End Developer | March 2013 - May 2013

- lead developer on Revolution Movie website
- developed website with Knockout.js
- integrated CSS3 animations
- integrated parallax scrolling effect
- fully responsive website via media queries
- integrated Grunt.js tasks for release packages
- taught employees how to use GitHub

Kobo FULL-TIME

UI Developer | May 2012 - March 2013

- worked on Kobo's Instant Reader web app built on Sproutcore JavaScript framework
- responsible for front end bug fixes and implementing new features to the application as needed
- worked with design/UX team to implement responsive design for all platforms
- used GitHub
- built research prototypes for potential widgets and functionality in website redesign
- performance tested prototypes on devices
- managed site maintenance and improvements
- maintained documentation on internal wiki page
- collaborated with other teams to solve bugs or research on certain features
- collaborated with back end developers to implement full scale features to the Kobo's website

Sonic Boom Creative Media CONTRACT

Front End Developer | February 2012 – April 2012

- front end support for existing client websites
- go to person for all front end projects
- develop websites and application using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery
- some Photoshop retouching and/or manipulation of images

St. Joseph/Pi Media contract

Flash Developer | January 2012 - February 2012

- made modifications to sections of bell.ca using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- made modifications to a flash application for touch-screen kiosks
- · integrated design and functionality changes

Capital C CONTRACT

Front End Developer | December 2011 – January 2012

- front end development for multiple Facebook apps utilizing JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS and ASP.NET
- integrated multi-lingual support in Facebook environment
- built apps requiring authentication by the user via JavaScript Facebook SDK
- integrated designs into FB applications
- made modifications Infiniti and Nissan websites

Brightworks contract

Senior Flex Developer | November 2011 - November 2011

- met with clients and stakeholders
- developed financial application for RBC utilizing Yodlee framework
- prepared Yodlee package for online store release
- implemented designs and content

Blast Radius CONTRACT

Front End Developer | October 2011 – November 2011

- developed holiday catalog slider for Tommy Hilfiger using ActionScript 3.0, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- implemented designs and client feedback
- implemented SWF Address JavaScript for deep linking
- set up review and staging environment and deployment packages for online and internal releases

Research Now FULL-TIME

Senior Developer and Team Lead | July 2008 - September 2011

- met with clients, gave quotes, designed, developed, integrated, QA and deployed
- developed global Research Now framework for all custom survey tools
- met with clients for specification requirements, quotes on custom development
- responsible for design on all applications
- lead senior flash developer on majority of flash and team lead for North American flash team
- developed custom interactive survey applications
- developed flex real-time survey reporting application

Canwest/Alliance Atlantis CONTRACT

Digital Media Developer | October 2007 – June 2008

- made modifications to slice.ca and showcase.ca utilizing HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- lead flash developer on all flash and front end projects
- developed and integrated new flash components for internal use in AS3
- optimized classes for efficiency, reusability and extendibility

Dashboard CONTRACT

Digital Architect | July 2007 - September 2007

- lead flash developer on Wayne Gretzky project using HTML, CSS, and ActionScript 3.0
- took over for previous developers
- integrated back-end client driven CMS into Flash
- integrated SWF Address into flash websites for deep linking
- implemented all design concepts such as layout, animations, interactivity, and navigation

Mindblossom FULL-TIME

Intermediate Flash Developer | October 2006 - July 2007

- developed websites, games, and flash components using AS2 OOP
- developed to the strict deadlines, design and interface architecture principles
- implemented all design concepts such as animations, interactivity, and navigation into flash
- XML and audio integration

Engage Learning Systems CONTRACT

Flash Developer | October 2005 - April 2006

- project lead in numerous projects
- developed E-Learning modules using AS2 for high-profile companies
- XML and audio integration for e-learning modules
- manipulated and mixed audio files in modules to create a fully functional projects

EDUCATION

May 2001 - April 2004

Seneca College - Digital Media Arts

INTEREST/HOBBIES

stand-up comedy, playing basketball & volleyball, Game of Thrones, Walking Dead, Archer, Boardwalk Empire, Vikings, Shameless, hip-hop, playing PS3 and Xbox One, music production, love of pets and animals, fantasy basketball.